{"passage": ["In 2000, a neuroscientist at University College London named", "Eleanor Maguire wanted to find out what effect, if any, all that", "driving around the labyrinthine streets of London might have on", "cabbies\u2019 brains. When she brought sixteen taxi drivers into her lab", "and examined their brains in an MRI scanner, she found one", "surprising and important difference. The right posterior", "hippocampus, a part of the brain known to be involved in spatial", "navigation, was 7 percent larger than normal in the cabbies\u2014a", "small but very significant difference. Maguire concluded that all of", "that way-finding around London had physically altered the gross", "structure of their brains. The more years a cabbie had been on the", "road, the more pronounced the effect.", "The brain is a mutable organ, capable\u2014within limits\u2014of", "reorganizing itself and readapting to new kinds of sensory input, a", "phenomenon known as neuroplasticity. It had long been thought", "that the adult brain was incapable of spawning new neurons\u2014that", "while learning caused synapses to rearrange themselves and new", "links between brain cells to form, the brain\u2019s basic anatomical", "structure was more or less static. Maguire\u2019s study suggested the old", "inherited wisdom was simply not true.", "After her groundbreaking study of London cabbies, Maguire", "decided to turn her attention to mental athletes. She teamed up with", "Elizabeth Valentine and John Wilding, authors of the academic", "monograph Superior Memory, to study ten individuals who had", "finished near the top of the World Memory Championship. They", "wanted to find out if the memorizers\u2019 brains were\u2014like the London", "cabbies\u2019\u2014structurally different from the rest of ours, or if they", "were somehow just making better use of memory abilities that we", "all possess.", "The researchers put both the mental athletes and a group of", "matched control subjects into MRI scanners and asked them to", "memorize three-digit numbers, black-and-white photographs of", "people\u2019s faces, and magnified images of snowflakes, while their", "brains were being scanned. Maguire and her team thought it was", "possible that they might discover anatomical differences in the", "brains of the memory champs, evidence that their brains had", "somehow reorganized themselves in the process of doing all that", "intensive remembering. But when the researchers reviewed the", "imaging data, not a single significant structural difference turned", "up. The brains of the mental athletes appeared to be", "indistinguishable from those of the control subjects. What\u2019s more,", "on every single test of general cognitive ability, the mental athletes\u2019", "scores came back well within the normal range. The memory", "champs weren\u2019t smarter, and they didn\u2019t have special brains.", "But there was one telling difference between the brains of the", "mental athletes and the control subjects: When the researchers", "looked at which parts of the brain were lighting up when the", "mental athletes were memorizing, they found that they were", "activating entirely different circuitry. According to the functional", "MRIs [fMRIs], regions of the brain that were less active in the", "control subjects seemed to be working in overdrive for the mental", "athletes.", "Surprisingly, when the mental athletes were learning new", "information, they were engaging several regions of the brain", "known to be involved in two specific tasks: visual memory and", "spatial navigation, including the same right posterior hippocampal", "region that the London cabbies had enlarged with all their daily", "way-finding. At first glance, this wouldn\u2019t seem to make any sense.", "Why would mental athletes be conjuring images in their mind\u2019s eye", "when they were trying to learn three-digit numbers? Why should", "they be navigating like London cabbies when they\u2019re supposed to", "be remembering the shapes of snowflakes?", "Maguire and her team asked the mental athletes to describe", "exactly what was going through their minds as they memorized.", "The mental athletes said they were consciously converting the", "information they were being asked to memorize into images, and", "distributing those images along familiar spatial journeys. They", "weren\u2019t doing this automatically, or because it was an inborn talent", "they\u2019d nurtured since childhood. Rather, the unexpected patterns of", "neural activity that Maguire\u2019s fMRIs turned up were the result of", "training and practice."], "question_set": [{"question": "According to the passage, Maguire\u2019s findings regarding taxi drivers are significant because they", "answers": ["demonstrate the validity of a new method.", "provide evidence for a popular viewpoint.", "call into question an earlier consensus.", "challenge the authenticity of previous data."], "correct_answer_index": 2, "category": "Big Picture Question"}, {"question": "Which choice provides the best evidence for the answer to the previous question?", "answers": ["lines 6\u20139 (\u201cThe right... difference\u201d)\n(\u201cThe right posterior hippocampus, a part of the brain known to be involved in spatial navigation, was 7 percent larger than normal in the cabbies\u2014a small but very significant difference.\u201d)", "lines 9\u201312 (\u201cMaguire... effect\u201d)\n(\u201cMaguire concluded that all of that way-finding around London had physically altered the gross structure of their brains. The more years a cabbie had been on the road, the more pronounced the effect.\u201d)", "lines 13\u201315 (\u201cThe brain... neuroplasticity\u201d)\n(\u201cThe brain is a mutable organ, capable\u2014within limits\u2014of reorganizing itself and readapting to new kinds of sensory input, a phenomenon known as neuroplasticity.\u201d)", "lines 15\u201320 (\u201cIt had... true\u201d)\n(\u201cIt had long been thought that the adult brain was incapable of spawning new neurons\u2014that while learning caused synapses to rearrange themselves and new links between brain cells to form, the brain\u2019s basic anatomical structure was more or less static. Maguire\u2019s study suggested the old inherited wisdom was simply not true.\u201d)"], "correct_answer_index": 3, "category": "Evidence Support Question"}, {"question": "As used in line 18\n(\u201cbasic\u201d)\n, \u201cbasic\u201d most nearly means", "answers": ["initial.", "simple.", "necessary.", "fundamental."], "correct_answer_index": 3, "category": "Vocabulary in Context Question"}, {"question": "Which question was Maguire\u2019s study of mental athletes primarily intended to answer?", "answers": ["Does the act of memorization make use of different brain structures than does the act of navigation?", "Do mental athletes inherit their unusual brain structures, or do the structures develop as a result of specific activities?", "Does heightened memorization ability reflect abnormal brain structure or an unusual use of normal brain structure?", "What is the relationship between general cognitive ability and the unusual brain structures of mental athletes?"], "correct_answer_index": 2, "category": "Big Picture Question"}, {"question": "Which choice provides the best evidence for the answer to the previous question?", "answers": ["lines 21\u201322 (\u201cAfter... athletes\u201d)\n(\u201cAfter her groundbreaking study of London cabbies, Maguire decided to turn her attention to mental athletes.\u201d)", "lines 25\u201329 (\u201cThey... possess\u201d)\n(\u201cThey wanted to find out if the memorizers\u2019 brains were\u2014like the London cabbies\u2019\u2014structurally different from the rest of ours, or if they were somehow just making better use of memory abilities that we all possess.\u201d)", "lines 30\u201334 (\u201cThe researchers... scanned\u201d)\n(\u201cThe researchers put both the mental athletes and a group of matched control subjects into MRI scanners and asked them to memorize three-digit numbers, black-and-white photographs of people\u2019s faces, and magnified images of snowflakes, while their brains were being scanned.\u201d)", "lines 41\u201343 (\u201cWhat\u2019s... range\u201d)\n(\u201cWhat\u2019s more, on every single test of general cognitive ability, the mental athletes\u2019 scores came back well within the normal range.\u201d)"], "correct_answer_index": 1, "category": "Evidence Support Question"}, {"question": "As used in line 31\n(\u201cmatched\u201d)\n, \u201cmatched\u201d most nearly means", "answers": ["comparable.", "identical.", "distinguishable.", "competing."], "correct_answer_index": 0, "category": "Vocabulary in Context Question"}, {"question": "The main purpose of the fifth paragraph (lines 45\u201351\n(\u201cBut there was one telling difference between the brains of the mental athletes and the control subjects: When the researchers looked at which parts of the brain were lighting up when the mental athletes were memorizing, they found that they were activating entirely different circuitry. According to the functional MRIs [fMRIs], regions of the brain that were less active in the control subjects seemed to be working in overdrive for the mental athletes.\u201d)\n) is to", "answers": ["relate Maguire\u2019s study of mental athletes to her study of taxi drivers.", "speculate on the reason for Maguire\u2019s unexpected results.", "identify an important finding of Maguire\u2019s study of mental athletes.", "transition from a summary of Maguire\u2019s findings to a description of her methods."], "correct_answer_index": 2, "category": "Function Question"}, {"question": "According to the passage, when compared to mental athletes, the individuals in the control group in Maguire\u2019s second study", "answers": ["showed less brain activity overall.", "demonstrated a wider range of cognitive ability.", "exhibited different patterns of brain activity.", "displayed noticeably smaller hippocampal regions."], "correct_answer_index": 2, "category": "Detail Question"}, {"question": "The passage most strongly suggests that mental athletes are successful at memorization because they", "answers": ["exploit parts of the brain not normally used in routine memorization.", "convert information they are trying to memorize into abstract symbols.", "organize information into numerical lists prior to memorization.", "exercise their brains regularly through puzzles and other mental challenges."], "correct_answer_index": 0, "category": "Inference Question"}, {"question": "Which choice provides the best evidence for the answer to the previous question?", "answers": ["lines 52\u201357 (\u201cSurprisingly... way-finding\u201d)\n(\u201cSurprisingly, when the mental athletes were learning new information, they were engaging several regions of the brain known to be involved in two specific tasks: visual memory and spatial navigation, including the same right posterior hippocampal region that the London cabbies had enlarged with all their daily way-finding.\u201d)", "line 57 (\u201cAt first... sense\u201d)\n(\u201cAt first glance, this wouldn\u2019t seem to make any sense.\u201d)", "lines 62\u201363 (\u201cMaguire... memorized\u201d)\n(\u201cMaguire and her team asked the mental athletes to describe exactly what was going through their minds as they memorized.\u201d)", "lines 66\u201368 (\u201cThey... childhood\u201d)\n(\u201cThey weren\u2019t doing this automatically, or because it was an inborn talent they\u2019d nurtured since childhood.\u201d)"], "correct_answer_index": 0, "category": "Evidence Support Question"}, {"question": "The questions in lines 57\u201361\n(\u201cWhy would mental athletes be conjuring images in their mind\u2019s eye when they were trying to learn three-digit numbers? Why should they be navigating like London cabbies when they\u2019re supposed to be remembering the shapes of snowflakes?\u201d)\n primarily serve to", "answers": ["raise doubts about the reliability of the conclusions reached by Maguire.", "emphasize and elaborate on an initially puzzling result of Maguire\u2019s study of mental athletes.", "imply that Maguire\u2019s findings undermine earlier studies of the same phenomenon.", "introduce and explain a connection between Maguire\u2019s two studies and her earlier work."], "correct_answer_index": 1, "category": "Big Picture Question"}]}